Kamil Janowski

Experienced full stack developer and an active OpenSource contributor. Working mostly with Java and Node.js, as well as Angular and React for the front-end, with a passion for DevOps and test automation.

Helsinki, Finland +358 40 667 3825 kgjanowski@gmail.com

EXPERIENCE

Reaktor Innovations Oy, Helsinki (Finland) - Hands on Solution Architect

July 2022 - PRESENT

Delta airlines

- Design and development of highly-available on-board entertainment system
- Reduction of technical debt
- Numerous data security fixes
- Reduction of operational costs
- Reduction of faulty deployments through the introduction of canaries
- Increase in performance and reliability of the service through the multi-region support and and chaos engineering

Technologies used: AWS FIS, Kinesis, DynamoDB, Lambda, S3, PostgreSQL, CDK, QML, React, Cognito

Paramount

- Design and implementation of ETL data pipeline
- Massive performance improvement, reducing the data batch ingestion time from a week to 30 minutes.

Technologies used: Snowflake, AWS Redshift, AWS SQS, AWS Lambda, Kubernetes, AWS S3, AWS Glue, AWS StepFunctions, AWS Athena, TypeScript, Argo Workflows

F-secure (Freelancing), Remote from Singapore for Helsinki (Finland) office

June 2021 - July 2022

- Development of in-house IoT solution allowing to issue remote operations to devices with installed f-secure product
- Proposed, designed and built aggregation gateway using GraphQL API, improving the performance for the user, as well as improving the overall development experience for other API developers, by limiting the need for data replication into their respective services as well as providing a common authorization layer
- Built infrastructure as code using CDK and CloudFormation
- Decreased the time to production by refactoring the CI/CD pipelines to use the blue-green and canary deployments

Technologies used: AWS Lambda, AWS ECS, AWS ECR, CloudFormation, CDK, nrwl/nx, TypeScript, DynamoDB, Aurora, Step Functions, AWS EventBridge, SQS, Jenkins, Groovy

SOCIAL

LinkedIn: kamiljanowski

Homepage:

https://www.kamiljanowski.com/

SKILL HIGHLIGHTS

Java, JavaScript, TypeScript, Selenium, REST, GraphQL, Spring, Hibernate, SQS, SNS, AWS EventBridge, AWS Step Functions, Lambda, CloudFormation, CDK, Serverless Framework, ECS, S3, RDS, PostgreSQL, MongoDB, Kinesis, Docker, Terraform, React, Next, Argo Workflows

EDUCATION

Master of Science (2016), University of Jyväskylä. Web Intelligence and Service Engineering (thesis)

Bachelor of Engineering (2013), Cracow University of Technology

Computer Science (thesis)

CERTIFICATES

AWS Certified Solutions
Architect
Azure Fundamentals
certificate
Coursera's Machine Learning
Course certificate

LANGUAGES

English - Fluent Polish - Native

F-secure (via Mavericks Oy), Helsinki (Finland) — *Backend Developer*

June 2020 - June 2021

- Developed incident management services providing an integration layer between services detecting malware based on the system events, and responding to specific detections.
- Participated in design sessions of the solution with our architects.
- Mentored junior teammates on using the right design patterns to improve reliability, performance, and maintainability.

Technologies used: AWS IoT, AWS AppSync, AWS Step Functions, GraphQL, AWS Lambda, DynamoDB, Lerna, JavaScript, TypeScript, AWS CloudFormation, AWS EventBridge, AWS SQS, Jenkins, Groovy.

Mavericks, Helsinki (Finland) — *Software Developer*

April 2020 - May 2020

 Developed internal tools for gig management in a serverless or functionless manner, relying on AWS to do all the heavy lifting without introducing any unnecessary custom logic.

Technologies used: Google OAuth2, AWS Cognito, AWS DynamoDB, AWS Lambda, SQS, AWS Api Gateway, OpenAPI, Lerna, Ruby, Node.js, TypeScript, JavaScript, Github Actions, Jest, Terraform, React, Next.js

Hatch Entertainment (via Mavericks Oy), Espoo (Finland) — *Software Developer*

September 2019 - April 2020

 Developed the Hatch game streaming backend, and an Angular based user interface allowing Hatch administrators to configure the application. Focusing on the numerous billing integrations, configuration management, and end-to-end test automation.

During my short adventure at Hatch, I also:

- Increased the test coverage from 0% to 55% by writing mostly REST-level and end-to-end tests.
- Spearheaded the migration from JavaScript to TypeScript.

These allowed the company to identify a number of major bugs that had been plaguing the project for a long time.

Technologies used: Java 8, Kotlin, Maven, Gradle, JavaScript, TypeScript, Lerna, BigQuery, MongoDB, Redis, Docker, Jenkins, CircleCI, Jasmine, express.js, mocha, chai, sinon, socket.io, Twilio, Neo4j, Protractor, Appium